Bloody kids.
诗厥的小匈
How fastidious you've become, Wormtail.
你现在还真讲究啊，器尾
As I[ recall, you once called the nearest gutter pipe home.
我记得你以前都是住在下水道里
Could it be that the task of nursing me has become wearisome for you?
难道你对照颂我 已经感到屡烦了吗?
Oh, no. No, no, my Lord Voldemort.
不…伏地魔王
...perhaps if we were to do it without the boy.
或许不靠那个男孩 我们也能做得到
No! The boy is everything!
不，那个男孩是最重要的
It cannot be done without him. And it will be done.
没有他就不能成功了 你们一定要做到
Exactly as I said.
要照我说的去做
-l will not disappoint you, my Lord. -Good.
-我不会让你失望的，我的主人 -很好
First, gather our old comrades.
召集我们的人吧
Send them a sign.
我要发信号给他们
Nagini tells me the old Muggle caretaker...
娜吉尼告诉我 这问房子的脐瓜管理员…
...is standing just outside the door.
现在就站在我们的门外
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
给我由一录去，右尾 让我好好获迎我们的客人
Avada Kedavra!l
呵蛙咀喀咀啦
Harry.
哈利…
Harry!
哈利!
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Hermione. Bad dream.
妙慎，我做恶萝了
-When did you get here? -Just now. You?
-姬敌时候到的 -刚到，你呢?
Last night.
昨天晚上
Wake up! Wake up, Ronald!
起床了，起床了，沫思
Bloody hell.
搞什么鬼啊
Honestly, get dressed.
快点把衣服穿好
And don't go back to sleep.
不要再躺回去睡了
Come on, Ron! Your mother says breakfast’s ready!
快点啊 ! 沫思 你妈妈已经把早餐做好了
-Ron, where are we actually going? -Don’t know.
-紫思，我们到底要去哪里? -我不知道
-Hey, Dad. Where are we going? -Haven't the foggiest.
-爸，我们要去哪里? -我也不知道
Keep up!
快跟好 !
Arthur!
亚瑟
It’s about time, son.
你们总算来了，年轻人
Sorry, Amos. Some of us had a bit of a sleepy start.
抱菊了，阿黑 有人今天早上睡过头了
This is Amos Diggory, everyone. Works with me at the Ministry.
孩子们，这是阿默迪哥里 我们一起在魔法部工作
And this strapping young lad must be Cedric, am I right?
这个健壮的小伙子肯定是西追
Yes, sir.
是的
This way.
请往这示走
Merlin’s beard! You must be Harry Potter.
梅林的明子啊 ! 你一定是哈利波特
-Yes, sir. -Great, great pleasure.
-是的，先生 -真是太和荣幸了
Pleasure to meet you too, sir.
我也很某幸认识你
Yes, it’s just over there.
大家注意，东西就在这儿了
-Shall we? -Oh, yeah.
-可以了吗? -可以了
We don't want to be late.
快点，我们可不能逮到了
Come on. Nearly there now. Get yourself into a good position.
快啊，大家快通去 各自找一个位子站好
Why are they all standing around that manky old boot?
他们为什么要图著 那个县朋的善蒜子?
-That isn't just any manky old boot. -It's a Portkey.
-那不是普通的就子 -那是港口给
Time to go!
该走了
What's a Portkey?
什么是港口给?
-Ready! After three. One, two... -Harry!
-预备 ! 数到三，一、二… -哈利!
...three!
二了 -一
Let go, kids!
放手吧，和孩子们 !
-What?! -Let go!
-什么? -放手 !
V'll bet that cleared your sinuses, eh?
肯定你们鼻子都昌通了吧
-Total shambles, as per usual. -Thanks.
-大家还是跟以前一样惨分分的 -谢了
Go on, look at that!
看看这场面 !
Well, kids, welcome to the Quidditch World Cup!
好了“，和孩子们 炊迎来到魁地奇世界番 !
Stay together! Keep up, girls!
不要走散了，跟上来，小姐们!
Look!
你们看 !
Come on! Keep up, girls!
惧跟上来，小姐们
Blimey!
吸呀 !
Parting of the ways, I think, old chap.
我们得先分天走了，老兄弟
-See you at the match. -See you.
-我们比赛的时候见了 -再见
-Cedric. -Ced, come on.
-西候 -西追，走了
See you later, Cedric.
再见了，西追
Home sweet home.
我们甜蜜的家
What?
什么?
-Excellent, excellent. -Ginny, look!
-太棒了 -金妮，你看 !
-All to the bath. -Look.
-去洗澡了 -快看 !
Girls, choose a bunk and unpack.
小姐们，跑好床铺整理行李
Ron, get out of the kitchen. We're all hungry.
从恩，快元并府房 我们都饿死了
-Yeah, get out of the kitchen, Ron! -Feet off the table!
-快玖并证房 ! 楷思 -有从桌子上移并 !
Il love magic.
魔法印呆了
Get your Quidditch World Cup programs here!
快来买世界和慢节目表
Blimey, Dad. How far up are we?
天啊，和爸，我们的座位有多高啊?
Well, put it this way:
这样说吧
If it rains...
下雨的时候…
..-you'll be the first to know.
你们会是第一个知道的
Father and I are in the minister's box...
我爸跟我的座位在部长的包抽里…
...by personal invitation of Cornelius Fudge himself.
是夫子他亲自邀请我们过去的
Don’t boast, Draco.
别太骑合了，践可
There’s no need with these people.
跟他们这种人没什么好说的
Do enjoy yourself, won't you?
好好享受吧
While you can.
趁你们还可以的时候
Come on up. Take your seats. I told you these seats would be worth waiting for.
快上来，到位子上坐好 告诉你们，这些位子保证值回标价
Come on!
来吧
It’s the Irish! There’s Troy!
这是爱尔兰队，那是崔洛
-And Mullet! -And Moran!
-那是穆莉! -还有英戎!
freland! Ireland! freland!
爱尔兰…
-Here come the Bulgarians! -Yes!
-保加利亚队来了 ! -太棒了
Who's that?
那是谁呵?
That, sis, is the best Seeker in the world.
那是全世界最棒的搜捕手
Krum! Krum! Krum!
喀浪【喀浪 1 喀浪上
Krum!
喀浪!
Yes!
好极了 !
Good evening!
大家晚安 !
As Minister for Magic...
身为魔法部长…
... it gives me great pleasure...
我非常地荣幸…
...to welcome each and every one of you...
炊迎大家来到这个地方…
...to the final of the 422nd Quidditch World Cup!
参加第4 2 2届 魁地奇世界番的总决赛 !
Let the match...
我宣做比赛…
.. begin!
开始 !
Krum! Krum! Krum!
喀浪【喀浪 1 喀浪上
There's no one like Krum.
喀浪好属害喔
-Krum? -Dumb Krum?
-喀浪? -奏喀浪?
He’s like a bird, the way he rides the wind.
他就跟岛一样 ， 可以习行
-He’s more than an athlete. -Dumb Krum.
-他已经不是运动员了 -春喀浪
He’s an artist.
他是个艺生家
-l think you're in love, Ron. -Shut up.
-我想你党上他了，楷思 -闭跑啦
Viktor, f love you
喀浪，我爱你
Viktor, 1 do
我党你
When we're apart My heart beats only for you
当我们分并时 我的心腑只为你跳动
Sounds like the Irish have got their pride on.
爱坪兰队好像在做胶利艇行了
Stop! Stop it!
快停 ! 快停下来 !
It’s not the Irish.
那不是党南苦队
We've gotta get out of here. Now!
我们得郊天这里，快 !
Get out, it’s the Death Eaters!
快走，食死人来了
Get back to the Portkey, everybody, and stick together!
大家快去港口给 千万不要分散了!
Fred, George! Ginny is your responsibility.
弗雷，和在治 ! 金妮交给你们照顾了
Go!
快走!
Harry!
哈利!
-Keep up, you lot! -Harry!
-你们要跟上来 -哈利!
Harry! Harry!
哈利工哈利!
Morsmordre!
魔魔浆 !
Harry!
哈利!
-Where are you? -Harry!
-你在哪里? -哈利!
We've been looking for you for ages!
我们找你找得快累死了 !
Thought we lost you, mate.
还以为找不到你了
What is that?
那什么东西?
Stupefy!
吊唱失!
Stop!
住手!
That's my son!
那是我儿子!
-Ron, Harry, Hermione, you all right? -We came back for Harry.
-此轧、哈利、妙肢，你们都没事吧? -我们回来找哈利
Which of you conjured it?
谁把它召唤出来的?
-Crouch, you can't possi-- -Do not lie!
-柯路奇，他们不可能… -别说诬
You've been discovered at the scene of the crime.
你们都在犯罪现场被还到
-Crime? -Barty! They're just kids.
-犯罪? -巴坦，他们只是孩子啊
What crime?
什么犯罪现场 ?
It’s the Dark Mark, Harry. It’s his mark.
那是黑魔标记，那个人的标记
What, Voldemort?
什么，伏地糜?
Those people tonight, in the masks, they're his too, aren't they?
今天晚上那些带面具的人 也是他的人
-His followers? -Yeah.
-是他的手下吗? -对
Death Eaters.
食死人
-Follow me. -There was a man, before.
-跟我来 -之前有一个人…
There!
在那焉 !
All of you, this way!
所有的人跟我来
A man, Harry?
哈利:那个人…
Who?
是座?
I don’t know.
我不知道
I didn't see his face.
我没有看到他的脸
Packet of Drooble’s...
一包吹实泡泡糖…
..and a Licorice Wand.
还要甘草棍
On second thought, just the Drooble’s.
袋不金，我只要吹实泡泡糖就好了
-It’s all right, I'll get it. Don’t worry. -Just the Drooble’s. Thanks.
-没关像，我请你 -不用了啦，谢谢
Two Pumpkin Pasties, please.
麻烦给我雨个南瓜派
Thank you.
谢谢
Anything sweet for you, dear?
还想吃什么甜点吗?
Oh, no, I'm not hungry. Thank you.
不用，我不戏，谢谢
This is horrible.
真是太恐怖了
How can the Ministry not know who conjured it?
魔法部怎会不知道是谁召唤的?
Wasn't there any security or...?
难道都没有安全措施，或是…
That's what worried them so much. Happened right under their noses.
所以他们才会担心 竟然在他们面前发生
It’s hurting again, isn’t it? Your scar.
你的疤痕又在痛了，是不是?
I'm fine.
我很好
You know Sirius will want to hear about this...
天狼星一定很想匠了册这件事…
...what you saw at the World Cup and the dream.
关於你在世界鼻看到的 还有你的萝
Hedwig. There we go.
嘻美，快去吧,
Clear the runway!
清除跑道 !
Well, there’s something you don't see every day.
这种事可不是每天都有的
Well, now we're all settled in and sorted, I'd like to make an announcement.
大家都坐好了，也分配好学院了 现在我要宣做一件事
This castle will not only be your home this year...
这个城堡除了是你们 这一年的家以外…
...but home to some very special guests as well.
同时膛来了一些很特别的贵宰
You see, Hogwarts has been chosen....
因为起格苇兹已经入站为…
Yes, what is it?
什么事情?
Tell them to wait. Tell them to wait. Wait.
请他们再等一等，再等一等
So Hogwarts has been chosen to host a legendary event:
所以，堆格羔兹被选中 主办一个盛大的活动
The Triwizard Tournament.
三巫癌法大赛
-For those of you who do not know... -Brilliant.
-我想你们没有区过这个活动… -好棒虽
.. the Triwizard Tournament brings together three schools...
三巫辣法大赛是联合三个学校…
...for a series of magical contests.
附内一速串的魔法比赛
From each school, a single student is selected to compete.
每个学校都选出一个学生代表 艰加比赛
Now let me be clear.
不过我得先声明
If chosen, you stand alone.
被选中的人只能和壮自己
And trust me when I say...
相信我说的…
...these contests are not for the faint-hearted.
情弱的人绝对不谤合参赛
But more of that later. For now, please join me in welcoming...
其他的以和后再说明 现在，请跟我一起欢迎…
...the lovely ladies of the Beauxbatons Academy of Magic...
波巴洞魔法学校可壳的女士们…
..and their headmistress, Madame Maxime.
还有她们的校蕉，美心夫人
Bloody hell.
媚杂味呀…
Blimey. That’s one big woman.
天啊，好大的女人喔
And now our friends from the north.
接下来是我们北方的朋友
Please greet the proud sons of Durmstrang...
请欢迎德姆苦学校的男士们…
..and their high master, Igor Karkaroff.
以及他们的校长，依果卡卡夫
Oh, it’s Krum!
是喀浪
Blimey, it’s him!
天啊，是他 !
Viktor Krum!
维克多喀浪…
Albus.
阿不思
Igor.
依果
Professor Dumbly-dorr, my horses have traveled a long way.
如不利多校长 我们的轧走了大老焉的路
-They will need attending to. -Don't worry, Madame Maxime.
他们需要好好照刁 别担心，美心夫人
Our gamekeeper, Hagrid, is more than capable of seeing to them.
我们的猎场看守人海格 绝对有能力把煌们照顾好
But you know, Monsieur Hagrid...
可是你知道吗，海格先生…
...they drink only single-malt whiskey.
独们都只喝单一纯礁威士忌
You idiot!
白痪啊你 !
Your attention, please!
请大家注意 !
I'd like to say a few words.
我要对各位说线句话
Eternal glory.
永恒的沫殖
That is what awaits the student who wins the Triwizard Tournament.
这是赢得三巫大赛的学生所享有的
But to do this, that student must survive three tasks.
但是要多膀 参赛者必须通过三项任务
Three extremely dangerous tasks.
三项非常非常危险的任务
-Wicked.
-好耶
For this reason, the Ministry has seen fit to impose a new rule.
所以魔法部必须前来执行新规定
To explain all this...
为了说明比赛规则…
...we have the head of the Department of International Magical Cooperation...
我们请了国际魔法交流合作部的…
...Mr. Bartemius Crouch.
巴堤柯路奇先生来告诉大家
Bloody hell. It's Mad-Eye Moody.
我的天啊，那是疯眼穆散
-Alastor Moody? The Auror? -Auror?
-阿拉特称散 ? 那个正气师吗? -正气师?
Dark-wizard catcher. Half the cells in Azkaban are filled thanks to him.
就是捕捉黑巫师的人 阿茧卡班有一半的犯人都是他抓的
He’s supposed to be mad as a hatter, though, these days.
他那阵子真是疯狂到了极
-My dear old friend, thanks for coming. -Stupid ceiling.
-我亲爱的老朋友，谢谢你来 -好奎的天花板
Thank you.
谢谢
What's that he’s drinking, do you suppose?
他在喝什么啊，你知道吗?
I don’t know, but I don’t think it's pumpkin juice.
不知道，不过肯定不是南瓜汗
After due consideration...
经过深思熟虑以后…
...the Ministry has concluded that, for their own safety...
魔法部达成决议 为了安全考量…
...no student under the age of 17...
十七战以下的学生…
...-shall be allowed to put forth their name for the Triwizard Tournament.
不得委出他们的名字 参加本次举办的三巫同法
-This decision is final. -That’s rubbish!
-这是最后决定 -不公平
That's rubbish! You don’t know what you're doing!
-你知不知道你在说什么
-Silence! -They’re not too happy about that, then.
-安静 -大家好像都很不高导
The Goblet of Fire.
你们看到的是火鼻
Anyone wishing to submit themselves to the tournament...
想要参加三巫同法大赛的人…
..-need only write their name upon a piece of parchment...
只要把名字写在一月羊皮纸上……
..and throw it in the flame before this hour on Thursday night.
在礼拜四这个时间以前 丢到火焰里就行了
Do not do so lightly.
千蕊不要草率决定
If chosen, there’s no turning back.
被选中之后就不能回头了
As from this moment, the Triwizard Tournament has begun.
三巫辣法大赛，就从现在开始
Alastor Moody.
阿拉特称散
...Ministry malcontent...
魔法部的叛逆者…
...and your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
你们新黑魔法防案和本老旺
lam here because Dumbledore asked me. End of story, goodbye, the end.
我会来是因为如不利多找我来 我的自我介绍很简单就这些了
Any questions?
有问题吗?
When it comes to the Dark Arts...
说到黑魔法防窜和本
...[ believe in a practical approach.
我喜欢用实际的教学方式
But first, which of you can tell me how many Unforgivable Curses there are?
首先你们有谁可以告诉我 世界上有多少不赦加
-Three, sir. -And they are so named?
-有三种，教授 -为什么叫不赦加
Because they are unforgivable. The use of any one of them will--
因为这是不可原谅的咒语 凡是使用不赦呢的人…
Will earn you a one-way ticket to Azkaban, correct.
-将会永下被关进阿兹卡班里面 -没错
The Ministry says you're too young to see what these curses do.
魔法部说你们还太小 还不能见识这些响语
l say different! You need to know what you’re up against!
我不这记想 你们必须知道将要面对的东西
You need to be prepared.
必须做好准备
You need to find another place to put your chewing gum...
把口香糖炸到别的地方
...besides the underside of your desk, Mr. Finnigan!
不要放到桌子下面，斐尼乾先生
No way. The old codger can see out the back of his head.
不会吧，那怪人背和后有长眼师
And hear across classrooms!
我还匠得到你说什么 !
So which curse shall we see first?
现在，座先来说一个响话呢?
-Weasley! -Yes?
-本斯理 ! -有
Stand.
站起来
Give us a curse.
告诉我们一个咒语
Well, my dad did tell me about one.
我…我爸爸，他有跟我说过一种
The Imperius Curse.
绝模史
Oh, yeah, your father would know all about that.
对，你爸爸当然很清楚这个咒语
Gave the Ministry quite a bit of grief a few years ago.
这个咒语那允年 给魔法部带来不少麻烦
Perhaps this will show you why.
也许这可以让你们看看 是什么原因
Hello.
你好啊
Lovely little beauty.
可过的小姐
Engorgio.
暴暴吞 !
Imperio!
王荆令 !
Don't worry. It’s completely harmless.
不要怕，儿不会伤人
If she bites...
如果凶咬你…
...-she’s lethal.
你就死定了
What are you laughing at?
你笑什么?
Get off!
走开 !
Talented, isn’t she?
怨很隐明，对不对?
What should I have her do next? Jump out the window?
接下来要忽做什么? 从窗户跳出去吗?
Drown herself?
还是把自己淹死?
Scores of witches and wizards have claimed...
很多巫师跟女巫都宣称
...that they only did You-Know-Who’s bidding...
他们之所以会匠从那个人的命令
...under the influence of the Imperius Curse.
是因为受到横史的控制
But here’s the rub:
但有一个大问题
How do we sort out the liars?
我们要怎庆分辩座在说谎?
Another, another.
再来一个不赦咒
Up, up. Come on.
你站起来
Longbottom, is it?
你叫隆巴顿是不是?
Up.
起来
Professor Sprout tells me you have an aptitude for herbology.
芽菜教授说 你在草药学方面的表现很好
The Cruciatus Curse.
叫酷刑允
Correct, correct. Come, come.
没错，过来
Particularly nasty.
这个咒语很丽怖
The torture curse.
酷刑如
Crucio!
加咒虚 !
Stop it! Can’t you see it’s bothering him? Stop it!
住手 ! 你没看到他快要受不了了吗? 快住手 !
Perhaps you could give us the last Unforgivable Curse, Miss Granger.
或许你可以告诉我们最后一个不赦唤 格荫像小姐
No?
不知道?
Avada Kedavra!l
啊哇咀喀咀啦 !
The Killing Curse.
这是索命响
Only one person is known to have survived it...
至今只有一个人逃通这个响语…
..and he’s sitting in this room.
而他现在就坐在这个房间壬
Brilliant, isn’t he?
简直太神奇了
Completely demented, of course, and terrifying to be in the same room with...
他的精神完全不正常 跟他独处一定很可怕…
...but he’s really been there, you know? He’s looked evil in the eye.
可是他真的对抗通黑魔法 而且他还打败过黑魔法
There's a reason those curses are unforgivable.
那些咒语不可原谅是有原因的
To perform them in a classroom.... I mean, did you see Neville’s face?
竟然就在教室里使用 你们没看到奈威的表情吗?
Neville?
奈威?
Son?
孩子?
You all right?
你没事吧?
Come on. We'll have a cup of tea. I want to show you something.
来，我们喝杯茶去 我有东西要给你看
We're gonna be late!
我们要带到了 !
Come on, Cedric. Put it in!
来吧，西追，放进去吧 !
Eternal glory. Be brilliant, wouldn't it?
永恒的沫殖 当个傈出的人
Three years from now, when we're old enough to be chosen.
再过三年 等我们统大以后就可以获选了
Yeah, rather you than me.
对啊，我希望是你不是我
Yes!
陡!
Thank you, thank you.
谢啦…
-Well, lads, we've done it. -Cooked it up just this morning.
-我们成功了 -今天早上才调好的
It’s not going to work.
这样是没用的
-Oh, yeah? -And why is that, Granger?
-是吗? -为什么? 格苦人
You see this? This is an Age Line.
看到了吗 ? 这是年龄限制线
Dumbledore drew it himself.
好不利多亲自必的
So?
所以呢?
So a genius like Dumbledore couldn't possibly be fooled...
所以像如不利多这麻属害的人 怎庆可能被…
...by a dodge as pathetically dimwitted as an Aging Potion.
可翡又电大的老化药给骗了呢
-But that’s why it’s so brilliant. -Because it's so pathetically dimwitted.
-这才是它了不起的地方啊 -因为它又可翡又电春
-Ready, Fred? -Ready, George.
-好了吗，弗雷? -好了，和在治
-Bottoms up.
-乾杯
-Yes!
耶…
Yeah!
陡!
Yes!
太好了 !
Ready?
好了邑?9
-Yes!
-好了
-You said!
-是你说有用的 -是你说的
-Oh, right, you want a piece of me?! -l'll tear your ears off!
-你欠局啊你 ! -可恶，走天，我咏断你的耳条
-Now you're making me laugh. -Take this! Come on!
试试看啊 ! 来啊 !
Fight! Fight! Fight!
打工打工打!
We're “old school,” right?
我们是“老式的”，哼?9
Yeah, but you look older!
对，你看起来老很多
Sit down. Please.
请坐下
Now the moment you've all been waiting for:
现在是大家期待的一刻
The champion selection.
我们要选出六士
The Durmstrang champion is Viktor Krum.
德姆苦的同士是… 维克多喀浪
The champion for Beauxbatons...
巴波洞的网士是…
...is Fleur Delacour.
花儿戴乐古
The Hogwarts champion, Cedric Diggory!
韦格革兹的同士是西仍迪哥里 !
Excellent! We now have our three champions.
太好了 ! 三名同士都已经选出来了
But in the end, only one will go down in history.
不过到了最和后 只有一个人可以名留青史
Only one will hoist this chalice of champions...
只有一个人可以高举这同士村杯…
...this vessel of victory...
这就是三巫同法大赛的…
...the Triwizard Cup!
优胶奖番 !
Harry Potter.
哈利波特
Harry Potter?
哈利波特?
No. No.
不会…
Harry Potter!
哈利波特!
Go on, Harry.
去啊，哈利
Harry, for goodness sake.
哈利，快去啊
He's a cheat!
他作头 !
He’s not even 17 yet!
他还未满十七诚 !
-It's wrong, I tell you! -You French tart.
-你给我好好解释一下 -你这个法国佬
-Everything is a conspiracy theory with you! -Quiet! 1 can’t think!
-这怎庆回事 ? 剖不利多 -我也不知道
-Everything is a conspiracy theory! -I protest.
-这种事情简直是不可能发生的 -我们一定要抗议
-Harry. -I protest!
-哈利 -我抗议
Did you put your name in the Goblet of Fire?
你有没有把自己的名字丢到火鼻?
-No, sir. -Did you ask one of the older students...
-没有，教授 -有请高年级的学生…
-...to do it for you? -No, sir.
-帮你丢进去吗? -没有
-You're absolutely sure? -Yes. Yes, sir.
-你说的都是实话吗? -是实话
-But of course he is lying. -The hell he is!
-很明显他在说议 -他说的是实话
The Goblet of Fire is an exceptionally powerful magical object.
火番本身具有非常强烈的魔法
Only an exceptionally powerful Confundus Charm could have hoodwinked it.
只有法力超强的信任史 才有可能骗过它
Magic way beyond the talents of a fourth year.
四年级的学生 根本做不到这种魔法
You seem to have given this a fair bit of thought, Mad-Eye.
你好像对这件事很清楚嘛，瘦限
It was once my job to think as dark wizards do, Karkaroff...
我的工作就是 揣摩黑巫师的想法，卡卡夫
-...perhaps you remember. -This doesn’t help, Alastor.
-你一定还记得… -阿拉特，说这些没有用
Leave this to you, Barty.
这件事交给你决定
The rules are absolute.
我们必须尊重规则
The Goblet of Fire constitutes a binding magical contract.
火鼻的规则 所有的人都必须要遵守
Mr. Potter has no choice.
波特先生别乱选择
He is, as of tonight...
他从今晚开始…
...a Triwizard champion.
将成为三巫大赛的辣士
This can't go on, Albus.
我们不能让比赛府行
First the Dark Mark. Now this?
先是黑魔标记，现在又这样 ?
What do you suggest, Minerva?
你有什么建议?
Put an end to it.
把这件事做个了结
Don't let Potter compete.
不要让波特参赛
You heard Barty. The rules are clear.
你匠到巴坦说的，规则很清楚
Well, the devil with Barty and his rules.
别管巴堤跟他的规则了
And since when did you accommodate the Ministry?
你什么时候天始这麻配合魔法部 ?
Headmaster, I, too, find it difficult to believe this mere coincidence.
身为校长的我，也不相信这整件事情 只是巧合而已
However, if we are to truly discover the meaning of these events...
不过 如果想知道它背和后代表的意义…
...perhaps we should, for the time being...
或许我们应该，暂时决定…
..let them unfold.
让比赛继续进行
What--? Do nothing?
什么 ? 什么都不做吗 ?
Offer him up as bait?
不能把波特当成乌
Potter is a boy, not a piece of meat.
他是个孩子，他不是乌
l agree. With Severus.
我同意，继续比赛
Alastor, keep an eye on Harry, will you?
阿拉特，请你多照顾哈利
-l can do that. -Don't let him know, though.
-我会的 -别告诉他这些
He must be anxious enough as it is...
他一定会很不安…
...knowing what lies ahead.
如果让他知道可能发生的事
Then again, we all are.
老实说，我们也很不安
How did you do it?
你是怎庆做到的?
Never mind. Doesn't matter. Might’ve let your best friend know, though.
算了，反正也扰所谓 不过谭该先告诉你最好的朋友吧
-Let you know what? -You know bloody well what.
-先告诉你什么 ? -你很清楚我在说什么
I didn’t ask for this to happen, Ron.
我甘不想参加比赛啊，荣恩
Okay?
可以吗?
-You're being stupid. -Yeah, that’s me.
-你真是个策蛋 -我就是策
Ron Weasley, Harry Potter's stupid friend.
沫思本斯理 哈利波特的策蛋朋友
I didn’t put my name in that cup.
我没有把名字丢进火鼻壬
I don’t want eternal glory. I just wanna be....
我不想要永恒的某汐 我只想当一个…
Look, I don’t know what happened tonight, and I don't know why.
聘我说，我不知道今晚是怎订回事 也不知道原因
It just did.
反正就是发生了
Okay?
好吗?
Piss off.
践什么
What a charismatic quartet.
好迷人的四人组啊
Hello.
嗨，大家好
I'm Rita Skeeter.
我是朴塔史识
l write for the Daily Prophet.
我帮《预言家日报》写报导
But of course you know that, don’t you? It's you we don't know.
这些你们当然都知道了 可是对你们我一乱所知
You're the juicy news.
你们才是最棒的新闻
What quirks lurk beneath those rosy cheeks?
在美转的外表下 藏有什么隐疾呢?
What mysteries do the muscles mask?
在健壮的肌肉下藏有什么秘密
Does courage lie beneath those curls?
在优美的身材下藏有勇气吧?
In short, what makes a champion tick?
总之，丫士们藏有什么秘读?
"Me, Myself & I" want to know. Not to mention my rabid readers.
我真的很想知道 更别说我那些瘦狂的读者了
So who's feeling up to sharing?
好了“，谁想要跟我分享啊?
Shall we start with the youngest? Lovely.
那就从最年轻的天始? 好可过
This is cozy.
喔，真是温暖
It's a broom cupboard.
这壬是抬沉楚耶
You should feel right at home, then.
那你一定很快就罗惯了
Don’t mind if l use a Quick-Quotes Quill, do you?
你不介意我使用速记笔吧?
No.
不会
So tell me, Harry.
那告诉我吧，哈利
Here you sit, a mere boy of 12--
一个十二蕊的小男孩…
I'm 14. Sorry.
我十四诚了
--about to compete against three students...
马上就要跟三名学长比赛
..-not only vastly more emotionally mature than yourself...
可是呢 他们不但在精神上比你成熟…
...but who have mastered spells that you wouldn't attempt...
使用刀话的能力 比你所想像的…
...in your dizziest daydreams.
还要更加属害…
Concerned?
你担心吗?
I don’t know. I haven't really thought about it.
我不知道 我还没想过这个问题
Just ignore the quill.
不用管我的笔
Then, of course, you're no ordinary boy of 12, are you?
你也不是个简单的十二茂男孩
-Fourteen. -Your story's legend.
-十四功 -你是传奇人物
Do you think it was the trauma of your past...
你党得会不会是你过去的创伤…
...that made you so keen to enter such a dangerous tournament?
造成你渴望参加危险的三巫大赛?
No, I didn’t enter.
没有，我没有
Of course you didn’t.
那是当然啦
Everyone loves a rebel, Harry.
大家都喜欢叛逆小子
Scratch that last.
把刚刚那句话删掉
Speaking of your parents, were they alive, how do you think they'd feel?
说到你的父母，如果还在世的话 他们会有什么感觉呢?
Proud? Or concerned...
骑傲吗? 还是担心…
...that your attitude shows, at best, a pathological need for attention...
你的行为其实是病态的 想要吸引大家对你的注意…
..at worst, a psychotic death wish?
或者是一种自杀的渴望?
Hey, my eyes aren't “glistening with the ghosts of my past.”
我的眼神没有内炮著过去的幽二 好吗?
Harry, 1 couldn't risk sending Hedwig.
哈利，我不能冒险派早美通来
Since the World Cup, the Ministry's been intercepting more and more owls...
自从世界鼻结束以和后 魔法部就开始拉截更多的猎头魔…
..and she's too easily recognized.
嘿美太容易被认出来了
We need to talk, Harry, face-to-face.
我们必须谈一谈，面对面的谈
Meet me in the Gryffindor common room, 1:00 this Saturday night.
礼拜六晚上一点 在葛来分多的交谊廉等我
And make sure you're alone.
要确定没有别人在场
Sirius.
天狼星
P.S.2
对了
The bird bites.
这焦锅会咬人
Sirius?
天狼星?
Harry Potter, age 72...
今年十二蕊的哈利波特…
.. Suspect entrant in the Triwizard Tournament.
以可疑的方式入选三下大赛…
His eyes swimming with the ghosts of his past...
他的眼神闪炮著过去的费震…
..and choking back tears....
他强忍住省水…
Sirius. How--?
天狼星，你…
I don’t have much time, so let me get straight to it.
我的时间不多，哈利 所以我们直接讲重点
Did you or did you not put your name into the Goblet of Fire?
你到底有没有把自己的名字 委到火番里面去?
No!
没有 !
l had to ask.
我一定得问清楚
Now, tell me about this dream of yours. You mentioned Wormtail and Voldemort.
现在跟我说一下你做的那个萝 你提到了总尾跟伏地魔
But who was the third man in the room?
那房间里面的第三个人是谁?
-I don’t know. -You didn’t hear a name?
-我不知道 -你没贡到名字吧?9
No.
没有
Voldemort was giving him a job to do. Something important.
伏地魔给了他一个任务 很重要的任务
And what was that?
是什么任务?
He wanted...
他想要…
...me.
我
I don’t know why. But he was gonna use this man to get to me.
我不知道为什么 可是他想要利用这个人来抓我
But, I mean, it was only a dream, right?
这不过是一个萝而已，对吧?
Yes.
是的
It’s just a dream.
这只是一个萝
Look, Harry.
匠好，哈利
The Death Eaters at the World Cup, your name rising from that goblet...
世界番出现了食死人 还有火鼻吐出了你的名字…
...these are not just coincidences. Hogwarts isn’t safe anymore.
这些绝对不是巧合 起格革兹已经不安全了
What are you saying?
你是什么意思?
I'm saying the devils are inside the walls. Igor Karkaroff?
我的意思是，城堡祷有内战 会是卡卡夫吗?9
He was a Death Eater. And no one, no one stops being a Death Eater.
他以前是食死人 而且当了食死人的人永焉不会再回曙
Then there’s Barty Crouch. Heart of stone. Sent his own son to Azkaban.
还有织石心肠的巴坦柯中奇 竟然把儿子送进阿艾卡班
You think one of them put my name in the goblet?
是他们其中一个 把我的名字放进火看吧了?
l haven't a clue who put your name in that goblet...
我不知道会是谁 把你的名字放进火鼻…
...but whoever did is no friend to you. People die in this tournament.
但是那个人对你绝对不怀好总 参加三巫大赛很容易吕命
-I'm not ready for this, Sirius. -You don’t have a choice.
-我还没有准备好参赛 -你别扰选择
-Someone’s coming. -Keep your friends close, Harry.
-有人来了 -千菌别准并朋友太下，哈利
Who were you talking to?
-你在跟谁讲话?
-What? Who says I was talking to anyone? -l heard voices.
-什么 ? 我哪有跟谁说话 -可是我有匠到啊
Maybe you're imagining things. Wouldn't be the first time.
-那是你的错觉吧 -这又不是第一次了
You're probably just practicing for your next interview, I expect.
你大概在练习下次的记者芒问吧
Amazing.
太属害了
-Amazing! -Neville. You're doing it again.
-好棒 -奈威，你又开始了
Right, sorry.
吗，对，抱雪
"Magical Water Plants of the Highland Lochs"?
神奇的高地水生植物及其特性?
Moody gave it to me. That day we had tea.
我跟穆散喝茶那天他人和借给我的
It’s already been through enough people.
同样的话已经传遇太多次了
Why don't you just go and talk to him yourself?
你干嘛不自己去跟他说啊?
Ron, this is your problem, not mine.
沫轧，这是你的问题 不是我的
What do you want me to say again?
这次又要我跟他说什么?
Go.
反正你去就是了
Ronald would like me to tell you that Seamus told him...
哥思要我跟你说，西莫跟他说…
...that Dean was told by Parvati that Hagrid’s looking for you.
狄思说区落跟他说，海格在找你
Is that right? Well, you--
是吧…?
What?
什么?
-Are you sure you won't do this? -Do it.
-你确定要这麻做吗? -照做就是了
Dean was told by Parvati that....
狄思说区蒂说…
Please don't ask me to say it again.
拜旗不要再让我说一次
Hagrid’s looking for you.
海格在找你
-Well, you can tell Ronald-- -I’m not an owl!
丈可以告诉生思说… -我不是猎头魔
Did you bring your father’s cloak, like l asked you?
有照我说的带你爸的斗禾来吧?
Yeah, I brought the cloak. Hagrid, where are we going?
我带来了 海格，我们要去哪里啊?
You'll see soon enough.
你很快就会知道
Now pay attention, this is important.
现在注意册我说，这很重要
What's with the flower?
那些花是要干嘛的?
Hagrid, have you combed your hair?
海格，你梳头聂了是不是?
As a matter of fact, I have.
老实说，我是梳了
You might like to try the same thing now and again.
人偶尔总要做一点不一样的事嘛
Hagrid?
海格 ?
The cloak! Put the cloak on!
斗禾，快把斗禾披上去
-Bonsoir, Olympe. -Oh, Hagrid.
-了晚安，美心夫人 -海格
I thought perhaps you weren't coming. I thought perhaps...
我还以为你不会来了，我还以为…
...you had forgotten me.
你已经忘了我了
Couldn't forget you, Olympe.
我怎麻会忘记人呢
What is it you wanted to show me?
你要带我看什么 ?
When we spoke earlier, you sounded so...
当你跟我说的时候 你的语气职起来好…
..-exhilarated.
机奢
You'll be glad you came. Trust me.
你会很开心的，相信我
Can we get closer?
我们可以著近看邑?
Dragons?
龙?
That's the first task?
这就是第一个任务?
-You're joking. -Come on, Harry.
-你开玩笑吧 -别这样，哈利
These are seriously misunderstood creatures.
其实人们都误会这些龙了
Oh, crikey!
吸呀 !
Although, I have to admit, that Horntail is a right nasty piece of work.
不过我也得承认 角尾龙真是超级凶猛的怪黑
Poor Ron nearly fainted just seeing him, you know.
可情的沫思只是看了一限就党合了
-Ron was here? -Oh, sure.
-此思来通? 一 对 可可
His brother Charlie helped to bring him over from Romania.
他哥哥帮我们把龙从下马尼亚运来
Didn't Ron tell you that?
柴因没跟你说?
No, he didn't.
他没说
He didn’t tell me a thing.
他什么都没有跟我说
-You cheat, Potter. -You stink, Potter.
-波特作吏 -灿波特
-Good luck, Potter. -Potter stinks!
-祝你好运，波特 -特波特大痣人 !
-Cedric rules. -Thanks.
-西追一级棒 -谢了
Like the badge?
喜欢这个徽章吗 ?
Excuse me.
借通
Harry.
波特来了…
Hey! Read the badge, Potter!
波特，叭一下徽章嘛
Can I have a word?
可以谈谈邑?
-All right. -You stink, Potter!
-好呀 -波特，你这个烟人!
-Potter, you stink! -Harry Potter smells!
-波特，你痣适了 ! -波特臭今分 !
Dragons. That's the first task.
龙，那是我们的第一个任务
-They’ve got one for each of us. -Come on, Ced!
-每个人都要对付一条龙 -走了啦 ! 西追
Are you serious?
你是说真的?
And Fleur and Krum, do they--?
那花儿跟喀浪，他们知道吐?
-Yes. -Come on, Ced, leave him.
-知道 -走了啦，小追，不要理他
-Right. -He’s not worth it.
-好 -不要跟他浪费时间啦
-Read the badges, Potter! -Hey, listen. About the badges.
-波特，哈一下徽章 -匠我说，关於那个微章
-I’ve asked them not to wear them, but-- -Don't worry about it.
-我叫他们别戴上去，可是他们… -不用在总
It’s not like I try to blow things up, exactly.
我又不是故意要把东西炸掉的
It just happens a fair bit.
这种事很常见啊
You have to admit, though, fire's pretty fascinating.
你必须要承认火炎释吸引人的
You're a right foul git, you know that?
你是个超级大白闹，你知道唉?9
-You think so? -I know so.
-你真的那庆想? -这是我的感觉
Anything else?
还有别的事吗?
-Yeah. Stay away from me. -Fine.
-有“，元我下一点 -随便啦
-There’s Potter. Cheat. -Why so tense, Potter?
-波特来了 -脸色干嘛那订沉重? 波特
My father and I have a bet, you see.
你知道，我跟我爸打赌了
I don’t think you're gonna last 10 minutes in this tournament.
我赌你大赛开始和后挝不到十分钾
He disagrees. He thinks you won't last five.
但是他不同意 他说你撞不到五分镀
I don’t give a damn what your father thinks, Malfoy.
我才懒得管你爸是怎么想的，轧份
He’s vile and cruel. And you're just pathetic.
他摆鄙又冷酷 你则是超级可翡
-Pathetic? -Oh, no, you don’t, sonny!
-可悲?9 -不准你这榜，小子
I'll teach you to curse someone when their back is turned!
让你看看 从别人背后施响是什么下场 !
You stinking, cowardly, scummy...
你这个讨悦，采小又插吕的小人…
-Professor Moody! -...back-shooting--
-穆散教授 ! -萌生放冷莘…
-What are you doing? -Teaching.
-你…你在做什么 ? -我在教学
-Is that a--? Is that a student? -Technically, it’s a ferret.
-难道说，那是一个学生吗? -基本上，那是一头才貂
Stand still! Stand still!
不要动…
-My father will hear about this! -ls that a threat?
-我一定会告诉我爸这件事的 -你敢威帝我?
-Professor Moody!
-称散教授… -你居然敢威党我?
Professor!
教授 !
I could tell you stories about your father that would curl even your greasy hair!
你要是知道你爸以前做过什么 保证你嘛得屁滚尿流 !
-Alastor! Alastor. -It doesn’t end here!
-阿拉特 -这件事还没结束 !
We never use transfiguration as a punishment!
阿拉特学校规定 不能用伙形响处罚学生 !
Surely Dumbledore told you that.
如不利多一定有上告诉过你吧
-He might’ve mentioned it. -Well, you will do well to remember it.
-他大概有提近吧, -那你就应该访记在心
Away!
让并 !
You. Come with me.
你，跟我来
That's a Foe-Glass.
那个是仇散镜
Lets me keep an eye on my enemies.
可以让我注意天人的距踊
If 1 can see the whites of their eyes, they're standing right behind me.
如果我清楚地看到他们的限和白 那表示他们就在附近了
Wouldn't even bother telling you what’s in there.
我不想跟你讲里面装了什么
You wouldn't believe it if I did.
就算讲了你也不会相信
Now...
说说看…
...what are you going to do about your dragon?
你要怎么对付你的龙
Well, you know, I just thought I'd....
你知道，我在想…
Sit.
坐下
Listen to me, Potter.
聘我说，波特
Your pal Diggory?
你的好朋友迪哥里
By your age, he could turn a whistle into a watch and have it sing you the time.
他在你这个年纪的时候 就已能把哨子变成会报时的手刍
Miss Delacour?
戴乐古小姐呢?
She's as much a fairy princess as I am.
她是个迷人的属害角色 就跟我一样
As for Krum, his head may be filled with sawdust...
至蕉那个喀浪 头脑季单四肢发速…
...but Karkaroff’s is not.
不遇卡卡夫可不是哩
They'll have a strategy.
他们一定会想出对策
And you can bet that it will play to Krum’s strengths.
我敢打赌 喀浪到时候一定会全力以赴
Come on, Potter.
快想啊，波特
What are your strengths?
你的专长是什么 ?
I don’t know.
我不知道
Well, I can fly. I mean, I'm a fair flyer. But I....
我很会息 我臣得还不错，可是我…
-Better than fair, the way I heard it. -But I’m not allowed a broom.
-我是区说你起得不错 -但比赛时，不能用抬壳
You're allowed a wand.
但是你可以用魔杖
Bets! Place your bets!
下注，来下注
Bets taken! Bets taken here!
这里可以下注，快来下注
Step up, folks! Who fancies a flutter in today’s bloodbath?
有没有人要在 今天的血案发生前下注?
Smart money’s on Krum to survive! Any bets?
有谁要赌吗?
Yes, sir?
你好，先生
Ten-to-1 for Fleur. There you go. Thank you very much.
工0比工赌花儿赢 非常感谢你
Your attention, please.
各位女士各位先生
This is a great day for all of us.
今天天所非常好
Each of the three tasks involves very considerable danger.
本次三巫同法大赛的三个任务 都非常的危险
Please keep your seats at ail times.
请大家全程都留在座位上
This will minimize any risks you may be exposed to.
这样可以降低发生危险的可能
-Harry? Is that you? -Yeah.
-哈利，是你吧? -对
i'm sure we all wish our champions...
我确定我们都希望同士们…
-How are you feeling? Okay? -...the greatest of luck.
-你党得怎庆样，膛好吗?
The key is to concentrate. After that, you just have to--
你一定要专心比赛 然后你只需要…
Battle a dragon.
跟龙搏辣
Young love.
青春的爱情啊
.. Stirring.
感人
If everything goes unfortunately today...
如果今天发生了什么不幸的事情…
.-you two may even make the front page.
你们雨个都会上头条
You have no business here.
你没有资格进来这壬
This tent is for champions...
这个幅棚属於癌士…
.and friends.
跟他们朋友的
No matter. We've got what we wanted.
没关俐 我已经得到我要的了
Good day, champions. Gather round, please.
你们好，辣士们 请大家过来
Now, you've waited, you've wondered, and at last the moment has arrived.
你们等了很久，也不断地猜测 揭晓答案的一刻终藉来了
A moment only four of you can fully appreciate.
这一刻只有你们四个人 才会特别珍惜
What are you doing here, Miss Granger?
你在这壬干什么，格荫休小姐?
Sorry, I'll just go.
我…对不起，我要走了
Barty, the bag.
巴坦，拿伐子来
Champions, in a circle around me.
同士们请统著我图成一转
Miss Delacour, over here. Mr. Krum.
戴乐古小姐，这下 喀浪
And, Potter, Mr. Potter, over here. That's right. Now...
还有波特先生 对…这壬
...Miss Delacour, if you will.
戴乐古小姐，请拿一个
The Welsh Green.
威尔士系龙
Mr. Krum.
喀浪先生
The Chinese Fireball.
中国火球龙
The Swedish Short-Snout.
瑞典短吻龙
-Which leaves.... -The Horntail.
-现在只剩下… -角尾龙
-What's that, boy? -Nothing.
-你说什么? -没什么
The Hungarian Horntail.
多牙利角尾龙
These represent four very real dragons...
这些代表四头真正的龙
..each of which has been given a golden egg to protect.
每头龙都各守议著一颗金蛋
Your objective is simple:
你们的目标很简单
Collect the egg.
拿蛋
This you must do, for each egg contains a clue...
你们一定要做到 因为每颗蛋里都有线索…
..-without which you cannot hope to proceed to the next task.
没有拿到蛋的人 就无法进行下一个任务
Any questions?
有问题吗?
Very well. Good luck, champions.
好吧“，祝你们好运，月士们
Mr. Diggory, at the sound of the cannon, you may--
迪哥里，避到大克的声音之和后 可以上场了
Diggory! Diggory! Diggory!
迪牙里…
Three of our champions have now faced their dragons...
三名同士已经解决了他们的龙
.and so each one of them will proceed to the next task.
所以可以继续进行 他们的下一个任务
And now our fourth and final contestant.
现在坎迎第四位 也是最后一位参赛者
Harry! Harry! Harry!
哈利…
Your wand, Harry! Your wand!
你的魔杖，哈利，你的魔杖
Accio Firebolt!
速速前，火闪电 !
-Yeah! -Yes!
-耶! -太好了 !
Oh, my God.
天啊!
-Yeah! -Yeah! Well done, dragon!
-耶! -做得好
Yes! Yes!
耶工太好了 !
-Yes, Harry! -Knew you wouldn't die, Harry. Lose a leg.
-好耶 ! 哈利 -我就知道你不会死顶多断一人条腿
-Or an arm. -Pack it in altogether?
-或是一焦手 -被龙给毅了?
-Never!
-绝不可能 !
Shush!
安静 !
Go on, Harry. What's the clue?
快看，哈利，线索是什么?
-Who wants me to open it? -Yes!
-有谁希望我打开?9 -打开它 !
-Do you want me to open it?
-要我打开吗? -要 !
What the bloody hell was that?
那是什么鬼东西啊?
All right, everyone! Go back to your knitting.
好了，各位 回去做你们该做的事吧
This is gonna be uncomfortable enough without all you nosy sods listening in.
没匠到他在旁下问东问西的 我还真是不避惯
l reckon you have to be barking mad to put your own name in the Goblet of Fire.
如果你真把自己的名字丢进火鼻 你一定是瘦了
Caught on, have you? Took you long enough.
你终於懂了 这刻久才想到啊?
l wasn't the only one who thought you'd done it.
我又不是唯一怀疑你的人
Everyone was saying it behind your back.
大家都在你背后这广说
Brilliant. That makes me feel loads better.
太好了 你这样说让我觉得好多了
-Least ! warned you about the dragons. -Hagrid warned me about the dragons.
-最起码我有警告你龙的事 -是海格警告我关於龙的事
No, no, no, I did.
不对…是我
No, don’t you remember? l told Hermione to tell you...
难道你忘了吗? 我要妙杂告诉你…
...that Seamus told me that Parvati told Dean that Hagrid was looking for you.
西其跟我说芭蒂说 狄思跟他说海格在找你
Seamus never actually told me anything, so it was really me all along.
西英才没说关於龙的事 那是我想要跟你说的
I thought we'd be all right, you know...
我以为这样的话我们就能和好…
.. after you'd figured that out.
如果你想通的话
Who--? Who could possibly figure that out?
拜斌，座会想那广多?9
That's completely mental.
只有神经病才会这样吧
Yeah. Isn't it?
也没错
I suppose I was a bit distraught.
因为我对你有点抓狂
Boys.
男生都这样
-Hi, Harry.
-你好，哈利
Cho, Harry’s looking at you.
纪秋，哈利在看姬
Shush.
别笑
Look at this!
你看看这个
I can’t believe it! She’s done it again.
我真不敢相信 她又开始乱写了
“Miss Granger, a plain but ambitious girl...
“格苦像小姐 一个平凡钾充满又心的女孩…
...seems to be developing a taste for famous wizards.
似乎对知名的巫师特别有仙趣
Her latest prey, sources report...
她最新的猎物根据消息来源指出…
... is none other than the Bulgarian bonbon, Viktor Krum.
正是保加利亚之实，维克多喀浪
No word yet on how Harry Potter's taking this latest emotional blow.”
目前没有人知道 哈利波特会怎样面圣这个打击“
Parcel for you, Mr. Weasley.
你的包衷，和本斯理先生
Thank you, Nigel.
谢谢你，奈吉
Not now, Nigel. Later.
不行，现在不行，晚点再说
Go on.
走啦
I told him I'd get him Harry’s autograph.
我跟他说会帮他跟哈利要签名
Oh, look, Mum’s sent me something.
你看，我杂寄东西给我
Well, it does match your eyes. Is there a bonnet?
颜色很配你的眼睛 有没有附小花由?
Nose down, Harry.
放下来，哈利
-Ginny, these must be for you. -l'm not wearing that, it’s ghastly.
-我才不要穿呈，好醒喔
What are you on about?
你干嘛那床愉守?
They're not for Ginny.
那才不是给金妮的
They're for you.
那是给你的
-Dress robes. -Dress robes? For what?
-这是晚礼服 -了晚礼服? 干嘛用的?
The Yule Ball...
耶诞狂会…
..has been a tradition of the Triwizard Tournament...
是从有三巫同法大赛开始以来…
On Christmas Eve night, we and our guests...
在平安夜的时候呢 我们会跟所有的实窜…
...gather in the Great Hall...
聚集在大廉里面…
...for a night of well-mannered frivolity.
进行行为端正的狂款会
As representatives of the host school...
身为主办学校的代表…
...l expect each and every one of you to put your best foot forward.
我希望你们每一个人 都能金亿量地克制自己
...the Yule Ball is, first and foremost...
耶诞舞会最重要的一件事情…
...a dance.
就是跳舞
Silence!
请安静 !
The house of Godric Gryffindor has commanded the respect...
将近一千年来 葛来分多学院
...of the wizard world for nearly 10 centuries.
博得巫师世界相当大的阁重
I will not have you, in the course of a single evening, besmirching that name...
我绝不容许你们在短短一个晚上 就破壤这份茹重…
...by behaving like a babbling, bumbling band of baboons.
香头转向的手之舞之，足之蹈之
Try saying that five times fast, huh?
有本事跟著说五欢?
Now, to dance...
跳狂呢…
...is to let the body breathe.
就是要让身体喘口所
Inside every girl, a secret swan slumbers...
每个女孩心中 都藏著一名优雅的舞者…
...longing to burst forth and take flight.
渴望展露本性，大展身手
Something's about to burst out of Eloise Midgen, but I don’t think it’s a swan.
如果是艾药米金那种女生的话就算了 我可不觉得她优雅
Inside every boy, a lordly lion prepared to prance.
而每个男孩心 也都有一头猛狮等待奔趴
-Mr. Weasley. -Yes?
-本斯理先生 -有
Will you join me, please?
请跟我一起示范好吗?
Now, place your right hand on my waist.
来，把你的右手放在我的腰上
-Where? -My waist.
-哪里了 -我的腰上
And extend your arm.
-再把你的左…
Mr. Filch, if you please.
科七先生，厅烦你好邑?
One, two, three.
一，一，二…
One, two, three. One, two, three.
一  一 一、  一
Never gonna let him forget this, are you?
你们会让他一草子忘不掉吧 ?
Everybody come together. Boys, on your feet!
大家过来，男生们，通通站起来 !
Why do they have to travel in packs?
为什么她们都集体行动啊?
How are you supposed to get one on their own to ask them?
何时才会有落音的人让我们邀请?
Blimey, Harry. You've slayed dragons. If you can’t get a date, who can?
哈利，你列打败一条节 你都找不到舞伴，那谁能?
I think I'd take the dragon right now.
我宁可再去跟龙对抗
l take after my mum.
我是得到我妈妈的焉传
Though I didn’t know her very well. She left when I was about 3.
我对我曙很陌生 我三态的时候就没如
No, not the maternal sort, her.
老实说，她没有什么母党
Broke me dad's heart, though. He was a tiny little fella, my dad.
我爸爸心都碎了 他只是个普通的小个子
I could pick him up at the age of 6 with one hand and put him up on the dresser.
我六城就能锡把他抬起来 一焦手把他放在衣杠上
He laughed so hard at that.
这让他笑得很开心
Very funny.
我觉得很好笑
And then he died just when I started school, so....
然后我才开始上学他就死了
So I sort of had to make me own way, as it were.
所以接下来我必须靠我自己
But enough of me. What about you?
怎订都在说我，和呢?
This is mad. At this rate, we'll be the only ones in our year without dates.
真气人，在这样下去 我们会是全年级唯一找不到舞伴的人
Yeah, but, then again, he can take himself.
至少，他跟自己跳得很开心
It might interest you to know that Neville’s already got someone.
你们一定很有届直知道 奈威已经约到人了
Now I'm really depressed.
我觉得好温器虽
"Get a move on or all the good ones will have gone.”
“心动不行动，机会流失中
Who you going with, then?
那你的舞伴是谁啊?
-Oi, Angelina? -What?
-嘿，痢娜 -干嘛?
Do you wanna go to the ball with me?
你要不要跟我去舞会?
To the ball?
去舞会?
Yeah, all right.
好啊
Oi, Hermione.
妙恩
You're a girl.
你就是女生嘛
Very well spotted.
你眼力还真好
Come with one of us?
要不要跟我们其中一个去?
Come on. It’s one thing for a bloke to show up alone.
去嘛 男生一个人参加舞会没什么
For a girl, it’s just sad.
女生这样就翡哀唆
I won't be going alone, because, believe it or not, someone's asked me!
我不会一个人去 不管你信不信已经有人邀请我了
And I said yes!
而且我答应了
Bloody hell.
搞什记
She's lying, right?
她是骗人的吧?
If you say so.
你觉得是就是
Look, we've just gotta grit our teeth and do it.
区著 我们一定要咬紧牙关勇往直前
Tonight, when we get back to the common room, we'll both have partners. Agreed?
今天晚上回到交谊廉的时候 我们都要找到舞伴，同意吗?
Agreed.
同意
-Cho! -Harry!
-张秋 ! -哈利!
Watch yourself on the stairs. It’s a bit icy at the top.
展楼梯的时候要小心 上面都结冰了
Okay, thanks.
好，谢谢
Cho?
张秋?
Yes?
什么事?
l wondered if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
我在想你会不会 想跟我一起去参加舞会?
Sorry, I didn't catch that.
对不起，我没听清楚
l was just wondering if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
我是…我是想问你 愿不顾意跟我一起参加耶诞舞会
Harry...
哈利…
...[’m sorry, but someone's already asked me.
我很抱歉 可是有人先约我
Well, I’ve said I'll go with him.
我已经答应跟他一起去了
Okay. Yeah. Great.
这样啊，我知道了
Fine. No problem.
没关俐，没问题
Okay. Good.
好
Harry?
哈利?
..SOrry.
很抱雪
It’s all right, Ron.
不要和涌的，芝思
It’s okay, Ron. It’s all right. It doesn’t matter.
没事的，别看得那记严重嘛
What happened to you?
你怎么啦?
He just asked Fleur Delacour out.
他加蜀约了花儿戴乐古出去
-What? -What did she say?
-什么? -那她怎庆说?
No, of course.
当然是拒绝唆
-She said yes? -Don't be silly.
-准道她答应了? -别俐了
There she was, walking by. You know how I like it when they walk.
她就这样走遇去 你知道我最喜欢她们走路的样子
I couldn't help it. It just sort of slipped out.
所以我忍不住就关口约她了
Actually, he sort of screamed at her. It was a bit frightening.
其实，他根本是用吼的 那感觉对死人了
-And what did you do then? -What else? I ran for it.
-最后怎样了? -还能怎样 ? 我掉头就跑啊
I'm not cut out for this, Harry. I don’t know what got into me.
我根本不太会约女孩子 我不知道我到底是怎么了
-Hi, Harry.
-你好，哈利
l always liked looking at them from behind.
我只敢从和后面看著她们
She's never gonna forgive me, ever.
这下她永下不会原访我了
Hey!
哩 oo
Bloody hell.
太可怕了
Bloody....
好可怕…
Oh, bloody....
太可怕了…:
What are those? What are those?
那是什么?那是什么?
-My dress robes. -Well, they're all right!
-我的礼服 -看起来就很好
No lace. No dodgy little collar.
没有蕾缘，没有奇怪的领子
Well, 1 expect yours are more traditional.
我还觉得你的造型比较传统
Traditional?! They're ancient! l look like my Great Aunt Tessie!
传统? 简直有统老所 我看起来就像一个老太婆
I smell like my Great Aunt Tessie.
并起来也像个老太攻
Murder me, Harry.
负了我吧，哈利
Leave it alone!
不要再管你的领带了
Poor kid. I bet she’s alone in her room, crying her eyes out.
可情啊，她现在孤单的 待在宿舍里哭得跟什么一样
-Who? -Hermione, of course.
-谁啊? -当然是妙疏啊
Come on, Harry, why do you think she wouldn't tell us who she’s coming with?
拜旗，哈利 不然她为什么不说跟谁参加舞会
Because we'd take the mickey out of her if she did.
因为我们知道的话会取笑她
Nobody asked her. Would've taken her myself if she wasn't so bloody proud.
才没人约她呢 如果她不要自以为是，我就约她了
-Hello, boys.
-你们好
Don't you look...
你看起来…
...dashing.
钙呆了
There you are, Potter. Are you and Miss Patil ready?
你在这里呵，波特 你跟苑蒂都准备好了吗 ?
-Ready, professor? -To dance.
-准备什么 ? 教授 -并舞啊
It’s traditional that the three champions-- Well, in this case, four.
这是三巫大赛的传统 今年由你们…
--are the first to dance.
四个辣士负责开舞
-Surely I told you that. -No.
-我麻该跟你说过了吧? -没有啊
Well, now you know.
那你现在知道了
As for you, Mr. Weasley, you may proceed into the Great Hall with Miss Patil.
至於你，和本斯里 你可以跟帕玛小姐一起到大万守
-Oh, there you are. -Come on, then.
-你在这里啊 -走吧,
Come along this way.
我们往这下走
Oh, come on.
走啦
-Hi. -Now, I need you all to line up...
-喔，亲党的 -现在请你们全部排成一列好吗?
...in the procession, please. Oh, you are very late.
你们都速到了
This way. This way. Come along.
全部跟我来 来，走这史
She looks beautiful!
她看起来好漂亮喔 !
Is that Hermione Granger? With Viktor Krum?
那是妙时格苦公吗? 她跟喀浪在一起?
No. Absolutely not.
不，绝对不可能
Hi!
!
Harry, take my waist.
哈利，快点搂我的腰
-What? -Now!
-什么? -快!
Are you ready?
淮备好了吗?
Move your body like a hairy troll
像长毛巨人接气
Learning to rock and roll
学习怎庆揪滚
Spin around like a crazy elf
像精起满场赤
Dancing by himself
他自己一个人跳舞
Boogie down like a unicorn
像独角默踏开脚步
No stopping till the break of dawn
不到黎明绝不停止
Put your hands up in the air
把手臂高高举起
Like an ogre who just don't care
就像怪物一样不在乎
Can you dance like a Hippogriff?
能否跳得活像独身魔首菊
Ruddy pumpkinhead, isn't he?
这像伙一看就很讨屡
I don’t think it was the books that had him going to the library.
我现在知道他为什么常跑图书馆
May I have your arm?
我可以请你跳舞吗?
Arm. Leg. I’m yours.
可以啊，快内
Hot, isn’t it?
很热对不对?了
Viktor’s gone to go and get drinks. Would you care to join us?
维克多去拿饮料了 要不要加入我们?
No, we'd not care to join you and Viktor.
不要 我们才不要跟你还有维克多混呢
What’s got your wand in a knot?
你干嘛一副氛呼呼的样子?
He’s a Durmstrang. You're fraternizing with the enemy.
你竟然跟我们的散人交朋友
The enemy? Who was it wanting his autograph?
敢人? 是座说要他的签名照的
Besides, the whole point of the tournament...
而且三巫大赛的重业…
. is international magical cooperation...
就是要促进国际魔法交流…
...to make friends.
是为了要交朋友
I think he’s got a bit more than friendship on his mind.
我党得他的目的不只是交朋友
Are you going to ask me to dance or not?
你到底要不要请我跳舞 ?
No.
不要
-He’s using you. -How dare you?!
-他是在利用巡 -你太通分了 !
-Besides, I can take care of myself. -l doubt it. He’s way too old.
-再说，我自己会照顾我自己 -那很难说他年纪太大了
-What?! What? That's what you think? -Yeah, that’s what I think.
-什么 ? 这就是你的看法吗? -对，这就是我的看法
You know the solution then, don’t you?
那你知道该怎广解决吧 ?
-Go on. -Next time there’s a ball...
-说啊 -下次有舞会的时候…
...pluck up the courage and ask me before somebody else does!
在别人约我之前先鼓起勇气约我 !
And not as a last resort.
别把我当成最后手段
Well, that’s-- 1 mean, that's just completely off the point.
你加蜀说的话跟这件事没有关俐
Harry.
哈利
Where have you been?
你去哪里了?了
Never mind! Off to bed, both of you.
算了啦! 你们雨个都去睡觉啦
-They get scary when they get older. -Ron, you spoiled everything!
-女生长大以后都好恐怖 -楷轧，所有的气氛都被你角了
What's this about?
你们在吵什么 ?
No, don't let
不，不要错过
This magic die
神奇的一刻
The answer's there
答案就要揭晓
Let me see it again.
再让我看一次你的手
Yes, the time is close now.
对，时机就要到了
Harry, at last!
哈利，你终於来了
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
给我由一录去，右尾 让我好好获迎我们的客人
You all right, Harry?
你没事吧，哈利?
I just got in.
我才刚回来
Me.
我
Harry, you told me you'd figured the egg out weeks ago.
哈利 你说你妈个礼拜前就想出来了
-The task is two days from now. -Really? I had no idea.
-下个任务只剩下雨天了 -真的吗 ? 我完全没想
Il suppose Viktor’s already figured it out.
我想维克多已经想出来了吧
Wouldn't know. We don't actually talk about the tournament.
不知道 我们没聊过三巫大赛的事
Actually, we don't really talk at all. Viktor’s more of a physical being.
其实我们根本很少在聊天 他比较喜欢肢体语言
I just mean he’s not particularly loquacious.
别误会，我是说他不太喜欢说话
Mostly, he watches me study.
他多半都在看我读书
It’s a bit annoying, actually.
老实说还疏烦的
You are trying to figure this egg out, aren't you?
你有努力在破解那颗蛋吧
What's that supposed to mean?
你这样问是什么意思?
It just means these tasks are designed to test you...
这些任务对你来说都是种考验…
...in the most brutal way. They're almost cruel.
不但蜂属而且还非常残忍
...[’m scared for you.
我很担心你
You got by the dragons mostly on nerve.
你很著险的才打败那休龙
I'm not sure it’s going to be enough this time.
不知道你这次膛会那订幸运吗 ?
Hey, Potter!
波特
-Potter! -Cedric.
-波特 -西候
How--? How are you?
你好吗?
Spectacular.
好得不得了
l realize l never really thanked you properly for tipping me off about those dragons.
我一直没有好好谢谢你 跟我说关於龙的事情
Forget it. I'm sure you would’ve done the same for me.
没什让 我相信换做你也会这广做
Exactly.
说得对
You know the Prefects’ bathroom on the fifth floor?
你知不知道五楼有个级长们的浴室
It’s not a bad place for a bath.
那里是个泡党的好地方
Just take your egg...
你可以拿著蛋…
..and mull things over in the hot water.
泡在热水里面好好思考一下
I must be out of my mind.
我一定是疯了
I'm definitely out of my mind.
我缀对是瘦了
I'd try putting it in the water if 1 were you.
如果我是你，就会把它泡进水里
Myrtle!
礁采 !
Hello, Harry.
吗，你好，哈利
Long time no see.
吗，好久不见了
l was circling a blocked drain the other day...
我有一天在塞住的水管里面晃
...and could swear I saw a bit of Polyjuice Potion.
我发普我看到了伙形药水
Not being a bad boy again, are you, Harry?
你不会又想做什么坏事了吧 ?
Polyjuice Potion?
伙形药水?
Kicked the habit. Myrtle, did you say, "Try putting it in the water"?
我已经没在用了“，玲条 你刚才是不是说“把它泡进水里” ?
That's what he did.
因为他就是这样做的啊
The other boy...
另外一个男生…
...the handsome one...
很印的那个…
...Cedric.
西仍迪哥里
Well, go on. Open it.
快点，打开吧
Come seek us Where our voices sound
到我高歌的地方找我
We cannot sing Above the ground
我无法在陆上歌唱
An hour long you'll have to look
只有一小时可以嫩找
To recover what we took
把我拿走的带回
Myrtle...
麦条…
...there aren't merpeople in the Black Lake, are there?
在黑湖里面有人急，对不对 ?
Very good.
你好属害
It took Cedric ages to riddle it out.
西追花了好久的时间才想到的呢
Almost all the bubbles were gone.
久得达这些泡泡都快没了
Harry, tell me again.
哈利，你再说一次
“Come seek us where our voices sound.”
“到我高歌的地方找我
The Black Lake, that’s obvious.
这是说黑湖没有错
“An hour long you'll have to look.”
“只有一个小时可以寻找
Again, obvious. Though, admittedly, potentially problematic.
这也很明显 这就是问题最大的地方
"Potentially problematic”?
“问题最大的地方?7
When's the last time you held your breath underwater for an hour, Hermione?
你什么时候可以申气 潘在水里一个小时啊
Look, Harry, we can do this. The three of us can figure it out.
聘我说，哈利，我们一定做得到 我们三个一定可以把它解天
Hate to break up the skull session.
我不想打断你们的动脑会议
Professor McGonagall wants you in her office.
不过上礁教授要你们去她办公室
Not you, Potter, just Weasley and Granger.
不是你，波特 只有本斯理跟格苦人
But, sir, the second task is only hours away, and--
可是，教授 准第二个任务只剩下网个锌头…
Exactly. Presumably Potter is well prepared by now...
没错 波特应该已经充分准备好…
..and could do with a good night’s sleep.
晚上可以好好地睡一觉了
Go. Now!
去吧，快!
Longbottom!
隆巴顿 !
Why don't you help Potter put his books back.
你帮波特把他的书放回去吧
You know, if you're interested in plants...
你知道吧，如果你想要瞳解植物…
...you'd be better off with Goshawk's Guide to Herbology.
最好从《高沙的药划指南》开始
Do you know there’s a wizard in Nepal who's growing gravity-resistant trees?
你知道尼泊尔有个巫师 竟然种出反地心引力的顶吗?
Neville, no offense, but I really don’t care...
奈威，我无意冒犯 不过我对植物…
..-about plants.
一点也不关心
Now, if there’s...
如果有什么…
...a Tibetan turnip that will allow me to breathe underwater for an hour...
可以让我在水里呼吸一小时的 西藏蒸芙的话…
...then great. But otherwise--
那就太好了 不然的话…
I don't know about a turnip. But you could always use gillyweed.
我是不懂蔽鞭啦 不过你可以用急鳃划
-Any bets? Any bets? -Come on, place your bets!
-要不要赌? 快…快来下注… -要不要赌?
Step up, mates! Don't be shy.
忌来下注，不要害姜
-Three lads. -One lady.
-三个男生 -一个女生
-Four go down. -But do four come up?
-四个人下水 -光个人会起来呢?
Don’t be so mean.
你们雨个好显劣喔
-Any bets? -Fleur’s 10-1.
-要不要赌，机会很大唾 -花儿的赂率是1 0比工
-You're sure about this, Neville? -Absolutely.
-你真的确定哮?奈威 -绝对确定
-For an hour? -Most likely.
-可以撑一小时? -差不多
Most likely?
差不多?
Well, there is some debate among herbologists...
现在还有一些事议 它在淡水的效用…
...as to the effects of fresh water versus salt water--
是不是跟鼎水一样
You're telling me this now? You must be joking!
你怎订现在才告诉我? 你在开玩笑啊?
I just wanted to help.
我只是想帮你
Well, that makes you a right sight better than Ron and Hermione.
至少你比生思跟妙梦有用多了
Where are they anyway?
他们十个跑哪儿去了?
-You seem a little tense, Harry. -Do I?
-你好像有些紧张 -有吧?
Welcome to the second task.
炊迎参加第二项任务
Last night, something was stolen from each of our champions.
昨天晚上有人偷走辣士们的实物
A treasure of sorts.
珍贵的宝物
These four treasures, one for each champion...
辣士们失去的这四样珍贵的宝物
...now lie on the bottom of the Black Lake.
现在就在黑湖湖底
In order to win...
同士们要赢得比赛…
...each champion need only find their treasure and return to the surface.
就必须找到他们的珍贵宝物 然后回到湖面
-Simple enough, except for this: -Put that in your mouth.
-规则很简章 -把东西放进嘴壬
They will have but one hour to do so, and one hour only.
他们必须在一个小时之内完成 只有一个小时
After that, they'll be on their own. No magic will save them.
之和后他们只能靠自己 没有任何魔法可以帮忙他们
You may begin at the sound of the cannon.
比赛在大克瑶结和后开始
-What's the matter with him? -I don’t know, I can't see him.
-哈利他怎庆了? -我不知道，我看不到他
Oh, my God. I've killed Harry Potter.
天啊 我害死哈利波特
Yeah!
陡!
What?
什么啊?
The Beauxbatons champion, Miss Delacour...
波巴洞的辣士戴乐古小姐…
..has unfortunately been forced to retire...
已经被迫退出比赛…
...80 She will take no further part in this task.
她不能参加下一障段的同法大赛
But she’s my friend too!
但是她也是我的朋友 !
Only one!
只能一个 !
Let’s get down below.
我们下去吧,
Krum! Krum! Krum!
喀浪【喀浪 1 喀浪上
Yes!
陡!
Ascendio!
升升降 !
Harry!
哈利!
He’s all right.
他没事
He’s all right. Barty!
他没事，巴堤!
-Go get him another towel. -l want all the judges over here now!
-再给他一人条所中 -请所有的评审现在过来 !
You saved her, even though she wasn't yours to save.
你救了她 你可以不救她，你务膛是救了她
My little sister.
你救了我妹妹
Thank you.
谢谢你
And you! You helped.
还有你，你帮了忙
Well, yeah, a bit.
是啊，帮了一点
-Harry! -Hermione!
-哈利! -妙起!
Are you all right? You must be freezing.
你没事吧，你一定姜壤了
Personally, I think you behaved admirably.
你的行为真的是值得尊族
I finished last, Hermione.
我是最后一个上来的
Next to last. Fleur never got past the Grindylows.
是个数第二 花儿没有通过那些滚带落
Krum! Krum! Krum!
喀浪…
-Come on! Come on! -Attention!
-大声点，再大声点 -注意
Attention!
请注意 !
The winner is Mr. Diggory...
胶利者是迪哥里先生…
...who showed innate command of the Bubble-Head Charm.
他齐越的运用氛泡头咒完成任务
However, seeing as Mr. Potter would have finished first...
由苍波特先生原本送巡领先…
...had it not been for his determination to rescue not only Mr. Weasley...
但是名因为他决定 救出卫斯理先生…
...but the others as well, we've agreed to award him...
跟所有的人而变得落后 所以我们决定给予他………
...second place...
第二名 !
-Second place! -Well done!
-第二名 ! -做的好 !
...for outstanding moral fiber!
以表扬他的高尚行为 !
Yes!
太好了
-Right on. -All that moral fiber, eh?
-太棒了“，哈利 -全是道德织维，哼?
-It’s great. -Moral fiber?
-真是太好了 -道德织礁?
Blimey. Even when you go wrong, it turns out right.
你蕉然做错决定，人种有了好结果
-Yeah, well done, Moral Fiber. -Congratulations, Potter.
-做得好，波特，表现出高尚行为 -茶喜你，波特
-A fine achievement. -Thank you.
-非常优秀的成就 -谢谢
Well done, boy.
做得好
-See you at Hagrid’s, Harry. -I'm sorry we haven't spoken.
-哈利，我们在海格家见 -很遗憾我们一直没谈过
After all, your story is one I've heard so many times.
蛙竞我不断匠说到你的事足
Quite remarkable, really. Tragic, of course...
非常了不起 当然也是一场悲剧…
...to lose one’s family.
就这样失去了家人
Never whole again, are we?
人生再也不完整了，对不对?
Still, life goes on...
不过，人生还是要继续
..and here we stand.
现在依然屹立
I'm sure your parents would be very proud of you today, Potter.
我相信你的父母 一定会为你感到天傲，波特
Bartemius!
巴惠1!
Not trying to lure Potter into one of the Ministry's summer internships, are we?
你该不是要请拐波特 署假去魔法部当实导生吧?
The last boy who went into the Department of Mysteries never came out!
上次进去的那个男孩 到现在都逮没出来呢 !
And they say I’m mad.
看看到底谁疯了
Now, I remember-- l remember when I first met you all.
对，我想起来了 我想起我第一次看到你们
Biggest bunch of misfits l ever set eyes on.
是我看过最不通谭的一群学生
Suppose you remind me of meself a little.
你们让我想到我自己
-And here we all are, four years later. -We’re still a bunch of misfits.
-但是四年之后我们依然聚在这壬 -我们还是很不迹应啊
Well, maybe, but we've all got each other.
或许吧，不过我们还是拥有彼此
And Harry, of course.
当然，至於哈利
Soon to be the youngest Triwizard champion there's ever been!
他很快就会成为史上最年轻的 三巫大赛的冠军了 !
Hooray!
好耶
Hogwarts, Hogwarts Hoggy Warty Hogwarts
韦格著兹…霍堆格格华华兹兹
Teach us something, please
请你教我一些知识
Mr. Crouch?
柯路奇先生?
A man has died here, Fudge. And he won't be the last. You must take action.
有人死在这里，夫子，他绝对 不会是最后一个，我们必须探取行动
I will not.
没有必要
In times like these, the wizard world looks to its leaders for strength, Dumbledore!
遇到这种状况，巫师世界要的 是一个强而有力的领导者
Then for once show them some!
那你就应该表现出强而有力
The Triwizard Tournament will not be canceled. I will not be seen as a coward!
三巫门法大赛绝不会取消 我不会让人家认为我是情夫
A true leader does what is right, no matter what others think.
真正的领导者不在乎别人怎麻想 他们只做对的事
-What did you say to me? -Excuse me, gentlemen.
-你说什么 ? 你罗列对我说什么 ? -对不起，琴位
It may interest you to know this conversation is no longer private.
你们或许会想知道 外面有人在匠你们谈话
Oh, Harry!
哈利
Harry, how good to see you again.
哈利，我真高浴再见到你
l can come back later, professor.
我可以等一下再来，教授
Not necessary, Harry. The minister and I are done. I'll be back in a moment.
没这个必要“，哈利 我跟部长已经谈完了，我局上就回来
Minister, after you.
部长，你先请
There you are. Your hat.
你的钻子
Oh, Harry, do feel free to indulge in a little Licorice Snap in my absence.
哈利，我不在的时候 你可以画情享受这些甘草糖果
But I have to warn you, they're a wee bit sharp.
不过我要警告你，它们有点辣
Professor?
教授?
-Professor. -Yeah.
-教授 一呵
Igor Karkaroff, you have been brought from Azkaban at your own request...
卡卡夫，我们照你要求 把你从阿辫卡班带来这壬
...to present evidence to this council.
在这个法庭上提出证据
Should your testimony prove consequential...
如果你真能提出重要证词…
...council may be prepared to order your immediate release.
法庭将会郑重考虑 减码或取消你的判决
Until such time, you remain in the eyes of the Ministry a convicted Death Eater.
在这之前魔法部还是判定你为 食死人的一分子
Do you accept these terms?
你接受这些人条件吗?
-I do, sir. -And what do you wish to present?
-我接受 -你要告诉我们什么 ?
I have names, sir.
我知道名字，庭上
There was Rosier, Evan Rosier.
他们是用西儿，伊凡吹西儿
-Rosier is dead. -He took a piece of me with him...
-中西儿已经死了 -死了? 他逮带走了我身体的一部分
-...though, didn’t he? -l didn’t know.
-不是吗? -这…'我不知道
-If that is all the witness has to offer-- -No, no, no.
-如果证人就只能提供这些…
There was Rookwood! He was a spy.
还有路克五，他是个间谍
Augustus Rookwood? Of the Department of Mysteries?
奥十斯都史克五 神秘部的用克五?
Yeah, the same.
对，就是他
He passed information to You-Know-Who from inside the Ministry itself.
他和从魔法部内部 偷出有用的资讯告诉那个人
Very well. Council will deliberate.
很好，法庭会做出决议
In the meantime, you will return to Azkaban.
这段时间你膛是先回阿兹卡班吧
No! Wait! Wait, please! Please, I have more! What about Snape? Severus Snape?
不，等等…求求你们，还有一个人 石内卜? 赛佛勒斯石内上下?
As the council is aware, I've given evidence on this matter.
法庭时就知道这一点 我曾经在这和里作证过
Severus Snape was indeed a Death Eater and, prior to Lord Voldemort’s downfall...
石内卜遇去的确是食死人 但是在伏地魔王败亡之前…
-...turned spy for us at great personal risk. -It’s a lie!
-他就已经冒著生命危险为我们做内谭 -他说议
-Today he’s no more a Death Eater than I am. -Snape remains faithful to the Dark Lord!
-现在，他跟我一样的清白 -石内卜对黑魔王还是很忠心 !
Silence!
姑静!
Unless the witness possesses any genuine name of consequence...
如果证人不能再提供法庭 任何有用的人名…
...this session is now concluded.
那这次的开庭就到此结束
Oh, no, no, no.
不行…
I've heard about one more.
我还知道一个
-What's that? -The name.
-一个什么? -名字
-Yes? -I know for a fact...
-说呀 ! -我知道有一个人
...this person took part in the capture...
跟其他人一起绑架…
..and, by means of the Cruciatus Curse...
另外还施展酷刑咒…
...torture of the Auror Frank Longbottom and his wife!
折磨正气师法苦克隆巴顿 跟他的太太 !
The name. Give me the wretched name!
名字，快告诉我名字 !
Barty Crouch...
巴堤柯史奇…
Junior.
二世
Hold him down!
快阻止他上
Get your filthy hands off me, you pathetic little men!
把你们的骨手放开 你们人这些诗灰的小人 !
Hello, Father.
你好，父亲
You are no son of mine.
你不是我儿子
Curiosity is not a sin, Harry. But you should exercise caution.
好奇心不是罪，哈利 不过你应该对好奇心冲愤
It’s a Pensieve.
这是储思伪
Very useful if, like me, you find your mind a wee bit stretched.
很有用的东西，有助於像我这种 脑子里装了太多东西的人
It allows me to see once more things I've already seen.
这可以让我再温袁 我看过的东西
You see, Harry, l have searched and searched for something...
哈利 我一直在努力寻找一些东西…
...-some small detail...
一些小细节
.. something I might have overlooked...
或是我忽略的东西
... something that would explain why these terrible things have happened.
一些可以解释这些恐怖事件 为什么会发生的原因
Every time I get close to an answer, it slips away.
每坎我快要找到答案的时候 答案又溜走了
It's maddening.
真是让我泪气
Sir? Mr. Crouch’s son.
教授，柯四奇先生的儿子
What exactly happened to him?
和后来他怎样了?
He was sent to Azkaban. Destroyed Barty to do it.
他被送去阿兹卡班 巴堤受到很大的打击
But he had no choice. The evidence was overwhelming.
但是他别扰选择 因为证据非常充分
-Why do you ask? -It's just that I....
-你为什么问这个? -是这样的…
l had a dream about him.
我曾经荔见过他
It was in the summer, before school.
那是在暑假的时候发生的事
In the dream, { was in a house.
萝中我在一个屋子里
And Voldemort was there, only he wasn't quite human.
伏地糜也在里面 但是他六不像是人类
And Wormtail was there too. And Mr. Crouch’s son.
盖尾也在里面 还有柯路奇先生的儿子
-Have there been others like this dream? -Yes.
-你还做过类似的萝吗? -做过
Always the same one.
每炊荔的内容都一样
Sir, these dreams...
教授，在这些萝里…
... what I see, you don’t think it’s actually happening, do you?
我所看见的 你该不会认为真有其事吧?
I think it’s unwise for you to linger over these dreams, Harry.
继续想著这些萝是不智的行为
I think it’s best if you simply...
哈利，我想最好的做法，就是…
...cast them away.
放下这些葛
It’s a sign, Severus. You know what it means as well as I.
这是一个微兆，石内小 你跟我一样清楚它代表什么
Potter!
波特!
What's your hurry?
你超著要去哪儿?
Congratulations, your performance in the Black Lake was inspiring.
茶喜你在黑湖的表现 真的很令人和敬证
Gillyweed, am I correct?
你是用色鳃草对吧?
Yes, sir.
对，教授
Ingenious.
真是天才
A rather rare herb, gillyweed.
急触划这种吏草很少见
Not something found in your everyday garden.
它在一般庭园是找不到的
Nor is this.
这个也是
Know what it is?
知道这是什么吗 ?
Bubble juice, sir?
泡泡果汁吗? 教授
Veritaserum.
这是吐真剂
Three drops of this and You-Know-Who himself would spill his darkest secrets.
只要三滴的剂量 就速那个人也会说出他最黑暗的秘密
The use of it on a student is, regrettably, forbidden. However...
很可惜这被禁止用在学生的身上 但是…
..-should you ever steal from my personal stores again...
你到再偷我私人储藏村的东西
...my hand might just slip over your morning pumpkin juice.
我枣怕会失手 滴引滴到你的早餐里面
-l haven't stolen anything. -Don't lie to me.
-我没有偷任何东西 -不要想驴我
Gillyweed may be innocuous, but boomslang skin, lacewing flies?
急触划或许没有别的用途 但是非洲枯蛇皮呢 ? 草晴岭吧?
You and your little friends are brewing Polyjuice Potion, and believe me...
你跟你的朋友们想调现变身水 相信我…
...[’m going to find out why!
我会查出原因
-Yeah!
一耶
Sonorus!
哄哄守 !
Earlier today, Professor Moody placed the Triwizard Cup deep within the maze.
今天稍早穆散教授已经把 三巫大赛的奖鼻放在迷宫的深处
Only he knows its exact position. Now, as Mr. Diggory...
只有他知道正确的位置 由苍迪哥里先生…
.and Mr. Potter...
以及波特先生…
...are tied for first position...
十个人六列第一名…
...they will be the first to enter the maze, followed by Mr. Krum...
他们可以最先进入迷宫里 接下来是喀浪先生…
-...and Miss Delacour. -Come on! Krum! Krum! Krum!
-还有戴乐古小姐 -加油 !喀浪…
The first person to touch the cup will be the winner!
先拿到痪鼻的人就是腾利者
I’ve instructed the staff to patrol the perimeter.
我已经指示教师们在周焉巡膛
Should, at any point, a contestant wish to withdraw from the task...
任何参赛者随时想退出这项任务…
..-he or she need only send up red sparks with their wands.
只要用他的魔杖 发射出红色的火花就行了
Contestants! Gather around. Quickly!
参赛者，请过来 快点 !
In the maze, you'll find no dragons or creatures of the deep.
在迷宫壬 不会遇到龙或是海底怪软
Instead, you'll face something even more challenging.
你们要面圣的是更严属的挑战
You see, people change in the maze.
人们只要进了迷宫就会有所改伙
Oh, find the cup if you can.
邵力哥找奖番吧
But be very wary, you could just lose yourselves along the way.
千万保持警党你们可能会在路途中 慢慢迷失自己
Champions, prepare yourselves!
月士们 做好准备 !
Good luck.
祝你好运
-My boy. -See you later, Dad.
-小追 -待会儿见
On the count of three. One--
数到三就开始 一
Fleur?
花儿 ?
Fleur.
花儿
Periculum!
号铝喀偷 !
Get down!
趴下
Expelliarmus!
去去，武器走!
No, don't! Stop! He’s bewitched, Cedric!
不，不要，住手 ! 他被施顺了，西追!
-Get off me! -He’s bewitched!
-帮开我 ! -他被施咒了 !
Yes.
好耶
Harry!
哈利!
Reducto!
吊唱失!
-Thanks. -No problem.
-谢谢 -不客气
You know, for a moment there, I thought you were gonna let it get me.
刚刚我还以为… 你会看著我被拉走
For a moment, so did I.
我的确有想过
Some game, huh?
黎人的比赛
Some game.
是很车人
Go!
走!
Go on, take it. You saved me, take it!
快去拿 你救了我，快拿
-Together. One, two... -Two...
-一起拿，一，二…. 一
-...three!
一一。
-You okay? -Yeah. You?
-你没事吧? -没事
Where are we?
我们在哪里?
I've been here before.
我来过这里
It's a Portkey.
这是港口给
-Harry, the cup is a Portkey. -I’ve been here before, in a dream.
-哈利，痪鼻是港口给 -我来通这和里，在莹中
Cedric! We have to get back to the cup. Now!
西追，我们必须回奖番那里 快!
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
-Harry! What is it? -Get back to the cup!
-哈利，你怎庆了? -快回奖鼻那里 !
-Who are you? What do you want? -Kill the spare.
-你是谁? 你要做什么? -把多余的人角了
-Avada Kedavra! -No! Cedric!
-啊哇咀喀咀特 ! -不 ! 西追!
Do it! Now!
快动手 !
Bone of the father...
父亲的骨枯…
..unwillingly given.
不知情的给予
Flesh of the servant...
仅人的血肉…
...Willingly sacrificed.
自愿奉页
And blood of the enemy...
再来是做人的血…
.. forcibly taken.
强迫取得
The Dark Lord shall rise...
黑魔王…就要重新…
. . again.
复活
My wand, Wormtail.
我的魔杖，器尾
Hold out your arm.
伸出你的手辟
Master.
主人
Thank you, master.
谢谢你，主人
The other arm, Wormtail.
另一焦手，器尾
Welcome, my friends.
坎迎我的朋友们
Thirteen years it's been, and yet...
已经1 3年了，不过…
...here you stand before me as though it were only yesterday.
你们站在我的面前 就往佛是昨天的事而已
I confess myself...
我应该老实地承认…
... disappointed.
我很失望
Not one of you tried to find me.
你们竟然没有人试图找我
Crabbe! Macnair!
克拉 ! 堆泰 !
Goyle!
高一 !
Not even you...
连你也是…
...Lucius.
和鲁休思
My Lord, had I detected any sign, a whisper of your whereabouts--
我的主人，只要察知您任何嘛象 或有您现身的风表我一定…
There were signs, my slippery friend. And more than whispers.
的确出现过踊象，我狐独的朋友 还不只出现风声
l assure you, my Lord, l have never renounced the old ways.
我跟您保证，我的主人 我从来没有抛素过去的作风
The face I have been obliged to present each day since your absence...
这张脸在您不在的期间 显现给世人的完全只是假象…
...that is my true mask.
这才是真正的我
l returned.
我可是有玫您啊
Out of fear, not loyalty.
你是出苍丽翼，而不是忠诚
Still, you have proved yourself useful these past few months, Wormtail.
不过，过去铸个月 你证明了自己还有利用价值，器尾
Thank you, master.
谢谢您，主人
Thank you.
谢谢
-Such a handsome boy. -Don't touch him!
-吗，多文英俊的男孩 -不要碰他 !
Harry.
哈利
I'd almost forgotten you were here.
喔，我差点忘了你也在这壬
Standing on the bones of my father. Yeah.
就站在我父亲的焉骨上
I'd introduce you...
我很想介绍你…
...but word has it you're almost as famous as me these days.
但是我由说这些日子以来 你就跟我一样有名
The boy who lived.
那个活下来的男孩
How lies have fed your legend, Harry.
这个传奇是多麻地上刹假，哈利
Shall l reveal what really happened that night 13 years ago?
我该不该说出1 3 年前那个晚上 到底发生了什么事?
Shall I divulge how I truly lost my powers?
我该不该说出 我到底是怎床失去我的力量的?
It was love.
那就是党
You see, when dear, sweet Lily Potter gave her life for her only son...
当亲爱的莉莉波特 为她唯一的儿子粕牲性命的时候…
...she provided the ultimate protection.
她就提供了最强的保访力量
I could not touch him.
我没有办法碰他
It was old magic.
那是古老的魔法
Something I should have foreseen.
我早谭该预知的
But no matter, no matter.
不过这和护所谓
Things have changed.
情势已经改沁了
l can touch you...
现在的我…
. NOW.
可以碰你了
Yeah.
就是这样
Astonishing what a few drops of your blood will do, eh, Harry?
你很茵证自己的绑滴血 所产生的作用，是吧?
Pick up your wand, Potter.
拿起你的魔杖，波特
I said, pick it up! Get up! Get up!
我叫你拿起来 起来 ! 起来 !
You've been taught how to duel, I presume, yes?
你有学过怎么决同对吧 ?
First, we bow to each other.
首先，对手必须互相鞠身
Come on, now, Harry. The niceties must be observed.
快点，哈利 你必须遵守这些细节
Dumbledore wouldn't want you to forget your manners, would he?
如不利多不会想看到 你忘记该有的礼貌，对不对 ?
I said, bow.
我叫你鞠躬
-That’s better. And now.... -No.
-这样才对，决门吧 ! -不要
Crucio!
加咒虚 !
Attaboy, Harry.
乖孩子，哈利
Your parents would be proud.
你爸妈一定会以你为傲
Especially your filthy Muggle mother.
尤其是你那豚朋的麻瓜母亲
I'm going to kill you, Harry Potter.
我要角了你，哈利波特
I'm going to destroy you.
我要徽底毁掉你
After tonight, no one will ever again question my powers.
过了今晚 再也不会有人时疑我的力量
After tonight, if they speak of you...
台了今晚，只要有人询到你…
...they'll speak only of how you...
他们只会说，你今天晚上是…
...begged for death.
怎样地求我角死你
And I, being a merciful Lord...
而我又是多广仁慧的…
...obliged.
成全你
Get up!
起来 !
Don't you turn your back on me, Harry Potter!
不准你背对著我，哈利波特!
l want you to look at me when I kill you!
我角你的时候，我要你看著我 !
I want to see the light leave your eyes!
我要看著你的眼神逐渐地黯淡 !
Have it your way.
就照你要的
-Expelliarmus! -Avada Kedavra!
-去去，武器走! -啊哇咀喀咀特 !
Do nothing! He’s mine to finish!
不准动手 ! 我要亲手角了他 !
He’s mine!
他是我的!
Harry, when the connection is broken, you must get to the Portkey.
哈利，束结断掉以和后 你要赶快跑去港口给
We can linger for a moment to give you some time...
我们只能速结一下子 帮你针取时间…
...but only a moment. Do you understand?
但只有一下子，懂吗?
Harry, take my body back, will you?
哈利，把我的属硒带回去好吗?
Take my body back to my father.
把我的必体带回去给我父亲
Let go.
放手吧
Sweetheart, you're ready.
亲党的，你准备好了
Let go! Let go!
放手 ! 快放手 !
Acciof
速速前 !
No!
不!
He did it!
我们赢了!
Harry!
哈利!
No! No! No, don't!
不要…
For God’s sake, Dumbledore, what's happened?
如不利多，到底怎广回事?
He's back. He’s back.
他回来了…
Voldemort's back.
伏地魔回来了
Cedric, he asked me to bring his body back.
西仍他要我把他的属体带回来
I couldn’t leave him, not there.
我不能丢下他 我不能
It’s all right, Harry. It’s all right.
没事了“，哈利 已经没事
He’s home. You both are.
西追回家了 你们雨个都回家了
Keep everybody in their seats. A boy has just been killed.
让所有人留在座位上 有个孩子被负了
The body must be moved, Dumbledore. There are too many people.
我们得把慌体超快移走 这壬人太多了
Let me through.
让我过去
Let me through!
让我过去 !
That's my son!
儿子，我的儿子 !
That's my boy!
儿子 !
-Come on. Get up. Easy, easy! -No.
-好了，波特，冷静点… -不要
This is not where you want to be right now. Come on.
你回到你想去的地方了 这来…
No!
不!
It’s all right, I got you.
好，现在没事了，有我在这壬
I got you. Come on. Easy, now.
有我在 走吧，冷静点
No!
不!
Are you all right, Potter?
你没事吧，波特?
Does it hurt? That?
怎订样，膛痛吗 ?
Not so much now.
没那刻痛了
Perhaps I'd better take a look at it.
或许该让我看一看
The cup was a Portkey.
那个奖番是港口给
Someone had bewitched it.
有人在上面下咒语了
What was it like?
感觉怎订样 ?
-What was he like? -Who?
-他的样子怎订样 ? -谁?
The Dark Lord.
黑魔王啊
What was it like to stand in his presence?
站在他面前感觉怎订样 ?
I don’t know.
我…我不知道
It was like I'd fallen into one of my dreams...
感觉就像是沉渝到基境里面…
.. into one of my nightmares.
进入某个恐怖的恶敌
Were there others?
那其他人呢?
In the graveyard, were there others?
墓地里还有其他人吗?
he.
我好像…
I don’t think I said anything about a graveyard, professor.
我好像没有跟你提过某地的事
“Marvelous creatures, dragons, aren't they?”
这些节很了不起，对不对?
Did you think that miserable oaf would've led you into the woods...
你想那个策海格会带你去风林壬吗?
.. if [hadn't suggested it?
如果没有我的建议?
Do you think Cedric Diggory would’ ve told you to open the egg underwater...
西追迪哥里怎庆会知道 叫你把蛋放到水里面再打开
.if [hadn't told him first myself?
如果不是我先告诉他的话?
Did you think Neville Longbottom, the witless wonder...
奈威隆巴顿那个策蛋
...could’ve provided you with gillyweed if ! hadn't given him the book...
如果没有我先给他那本书 怎庆可能会告诉你…
...that led him straight to it?
让他发现这件事 而用急鳃草 ?
It was you from the beginning. You put my name in the Goblet of Fire.
原来从一开始就是你 是你把我的名字丢进火鼻壬
-You bewitched Krum, but you-- -"But-- But--"
-是你兰喀浪施吕，可是… -可是…
You won because ! made it so, Potter.
你会赢都是因为我的安排
You ended up in that graveyard tonight because it was meant to be so.
你今晚会到那个墓地去 完全是因为有这个必要
And now the deed is done.
现在该做的都完成了
The blood that runs through these veins runs within the Dark Lord.
这些血管里的血 现在也在黑魔王的血液里流动
Imagine how he will reward me when he learns...
想想看他会怎床嘉奖我 当他知道…
...that I have once and for all...
我一荔永狗地人…
... silenced the great Harry Potter.
杀掉了伟大的哈利波特
Expelliarmus!
去去，武器走!
Severus.
赛佛勒斯
That’s it, take it.
喝下去
-Do you know who I am? -Albus Dumbledore.
-你知道我是谁吗? -阿不思必不利多
-Are you Alastor Moody? Are you? -No.
-你是阿拉特穆表吗? 是不是? -不是
Is he in this room? Is he in this room?
他在房间里吗? 在这房癌里吗?
Harry, away from there!
哈利，让并 !
-You all right, Alastor? -I'm sorry, Albus.
-你没事吧 ? 阿拉特 -抱坎，阿不思
That’s Moody. But then who's--?
那是穆散，那这是谁?
Polyjuice Potion.
伙身药水
Now we know who's been stealing from your stores, Severus.
现在我们知道是谁偷你的东西了
We'll get you up in a minute.
我们马上救你出来
Harry!
哈利!
Barty Crouch Junior.
巴堤柯路奇…二世
I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
如果让我看你的 我就让你看我的
Your arm, Harry.
你的手臂，哈利
You know what this means, don’t you?
你知道这代表什么意思吧?
He’s back.
他回来了
Lord Voldemort has returned.
伏地魔王他回来了
I'm sorry, sir. 1 couldn't help it.
对不起，教授，我没有闪法
Send an owl to Azkaban. I think they'll find they’re missing a prisoner.
送猫头魔去阿兹卡班 他们会发现少了一名囚犯
-l'll be welcomed back like a hero. -Perhaps.
-他们会像英雄一样获迎我回去 -或许吧,
Personally, I've never had much time for heroes.
不过我可没有时间隘英雄
Today, we acknowledge...
今天我们必须坦承…
...a really terrible loss.
一个惨痛的损失
Cedric Diggory was, as you all know...
大家都知道，西追迪哥里…
..exceptionally hard-working...
他非常的勤奋努力…
...infinitely fair-minded...
做人光明正大…
...a fierce, fierce friend.
他是个很患庆的朋友
Now, I think, therefore, you have the right to know exactly how he died.
因此，我认为 各位有权利知道他死亡的过程
You see...
没错…
...Cedric Diggory was murdered...
杀害西追迪哥里的人…
...by Lord Voldemort!
正是伏地魔王!
The Ministry of Magic does not wish me to tell you this.
魔法部不希望我告诉各位这件事情
But not to do so, I think, would be an insult to his memory.
但是不这麻做 就会侮昼我们对他的记居
Now, the pain...
我们和从这件悲剧…
..-we all feel at this dreadful loss reminds me...
所感受到的悲痛提醒了我…
..and reminds us...
提醒了我们大家…
...that while we may come from different places and speak in different tongues...
从然我们来自不同的地方 说著不同的语言…
..-our hearts beat as one.
但是我们的情感务是相同的
In light of recent events...
在最近的事件之后…
...the bonds of friendship we've made this year will be more important than ever.
我们在今年所结下的友谊 将比往年更加重要
Remember that, and Cedric Diggory will not have died in vain.
记住这一皮 西追迪哥里就不会白白粕牲
You remember that...
大家要记得这一点…
...-and we'll celebrate a boy who was...
我们将记住这样一个…
.and brave and true, tight to the very end.
勇敢以及真诚的男孩 直到永速…
I never liked these curtains.
我一向不喜欢这些惧慢
Set them on fire in my fourth year.
结果四年级的时候把它们烧掉了
By accident, of course.
当然是不小心的
I put you in terrible danger this year, Harry. I’m sorry.
今年我害你面临很丽怖的危险 我很抱歉
Professor...
教授…
...when I was in the graveyard, there was a moment...
我在蔓园的时候 某一个时刻…
..-when Voldemort’s wand and mine sort of connected.
就是…伏地魔的魔杖 跟我的魔杖速接起来的时候
Priori Incantatem.
呼呼，前加现
You saw your parents that night, didn’t you?
那天晚上 你看到了你爸妈，对不对 ?
They reappeared.
他们再度现身
No spell can reawaken the dead, Harry. Il trust you know that.
你要了解 世上没有可以让人复活的咒语
Dark and difficult times lie ahead.
黑暗与畦难的时代就要来酰
Soon we must all face the choice between what is right and what is easy.
我们很快就要面莉抉择决定 要走正确的路或是简单的路
But remember this:
但是你要记住
You have friends here.
你在这里有朋友
You're not alone.
你昔不孤单
Hermione.
妙恩
This is for you.
这个给你
Write to me. Promise.
写信给我，一定要富
Bye.
再见
Au revoir, Ron.
再见了，楷思
Do you think we'll ever just have a quiet year at Hogwarts?
你们想以和后还会不会 像今年这广不平静?
-No.
-不会
No, I didn’t think so. Oh, well. What’s life without a few dragons?
没有龙的日子不知道是什么样子?
Everything's going to change now, isn’t it?
从现在起一切都会不一榜了 对吧?
Yes.
对
Promise you'll write this summer. Both of you.
答应我暑假要高信 你们雨个都要
I won't. You know I won't.
才不会，人知道我不写信的
-Harry will, won't you? -Yeah. Every week.
-哈利，你会高吧? -会啊，每个礼拜都写
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN - R3]